{
    "id": "07ca90e126264a1aa9e6df665ada5c2e",
    "title": "Verbs Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "She ran with quick steps to the house when it …………………………. raining.",
            "description": "When the verb in the main clause is in the past tense, we use a past tense in the subordinate clause as well. ",
            "answers": [
                "start",
                "started",
                "had started"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "1c1e5fe6c97641e0af901d9b74bcfe68"
        },
        {
            "question": "It was so quiet you ………………………. hear a pin drop.",
            "description": "When the verb in the main clause is in the past tense, we use a past tense in the subordinate clause as well. ",
            "answers": [
                "can",
                "could"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "c0d096ac42494b5db169448b70f0eece"
        },
        {
            "question": "Susie ……………………………. with her sister.",
            "description": "We use the simple present to talk about permanent situations. ",
            "answers": [
                "lives",
                "is living",
                "has lived"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "a2f90d4908e54540a06f64c4aff98943"
        },
        {
            "question": "She ……………………………… in the film industry for fifteen years by next year.",
            "description": "The future perfect continuous is used to say that something will have been completed by a certain point of time in the future. ",
            "answers": [
                "will work",
                "will be working",
                "will have been working"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "fa565fa2be104ac6899b550ec01bd92a"
        },
        {
            "question": "The patient …………………………… before the doctor arrived.",
            "description": "The past perfect is used to talk about the earlier of the two past actions. ",
            "answers": [
                "died",
                "has died",
                "had died"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "91c1327d5645423bb010cecd6c6184e5"
        },
        {
            "question": "I …………………………………… this with him when he came here the other day.",
            "description": "The past perfect is used to talk about the earlier of the two past actions. The simple past is also possible here.",
            "answers": [
                "discussed",
                "have discussed",
                "had discussed"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "ee7c8b53669a481da15abb5b994ed895"
        },
        {
            "question": "When I was young, I .................................... play football a lot.",
            "description": "We use used to to talk about past habits. ",
            "answers": [
                "used to",
                "use to",
                "was used to"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "94e57f71e76b4a66b1f23e53c7410a3d"
        },
        {
            "question": "She ...................................... next month.",
            "description": "The present continuous is used to talk about pre-planned future events. ",
            "answers": [
                "gets married",
                "will get married",
                "is getting married"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "e3b86ace9a8e402fbd8ff8b496176d29"
        },
        {
            "question": "A good citizen ……………………………. all his financial obligations.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "performs",
                "is performing",
                "has performed"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "8009bdf72e1449da8fa85671900ed9de"
        },
        {
            "question": "He …………………………. in this office for ten years now.",
            "description": "The present perfect is used to talk about actions or situations that started in the past and has continued up to the present. ",
            "answers": [
                "worked",
                "has worked",
                "is working"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "ed15d3f81c7443a7b78785c2a0973982"
        },
        {
            "question": "You ……………………………… me you weren’t coming",
            "description": "Could have + past participle can be used to criticize people for not doing things.",
            "answers": [
                "would have told",
                "might have told",
                "could have told"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "9c60ea20bce94e4d87b53bdf037c6309"
        },
        {
            "question": "If a sinner …………………………… penitence, he can be forgiven.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "feels",
                "felt",
                "was feeling"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "ee83efa0774f4ee7aa163381890cc894"
        }
    ]
}